[upbeat electronic music]
【欢快的电子音乐】
♪ ♪
[eerie music]
[诡异的音乐]
- Imagine if you will,
- 想象一下，如果你愿意的话，
the town of Bikini Bottom.
比基尼堡镇。
Now imagine if everyone who
lived there was a robot.
现在想象一下如果每个人
那里住着一个机器人。
Submitted for your approval,
已提交供您批准，
a trip to Binary Bottom.
二进制底部之旅。
[whirring]
[呼呼]
[beeping]
[嘟嘟声]
[beeps]
[foghorn blares]
[雾号声]
[yawns]
[哈欠]
- I'm re-re-ready.
I'm re-re-ready.
- 我已经重新准备好了。
我已经重新准备好了。
I'm re-re-ready.
I'm red-red-ready.
我已经准备好红红了
[whirring]
[呼呼]
[beeping]
[嘟嘟声]
Morning, SpongeBot!
早上好，海绵机器人！
Ooh, you're looking
handsome today!
哦，你在找
今天好帅啊！
Mwah!
哇！
Aww!
[giggles]
[咯咯笑]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Ahh!
[munching]
啊！
[咀嚼]
- Meow.
- 喵。
- Good--good--good morning,
Robo-Gary.
- 好--好--早上好，
机器人加里。
[munching]
[咀嚼]
[gulps]
[吞咽]
- Mroww!
- 呜哇！
[meowing]
- [laughs]
[喵喵叫]
- [笑]
Oh, you wanna play.
哦，你想玩。
I know what you want.
我知道你想要什么。
- [meowing]
- [喵喵叫]
- Gary, be gentle
with the little laser!
- 加里，温柔点
用小激光！
- [growling]
- [咆哮]
- Ehh.
- 呃。
[beeping]
[嘟嘟声]
[foghorn blares]
- Oh!
[雾号声]
- 哦！
Time for work, Gary.
工作时间到了，加里。
I'll play with you
more when I get home.
我和你一起玩
当我回家时更多。
- Aww.
[vocalizing]
- 哇。
[发声]
Ah!
- Ooh!
啊!
- 哦！
- Meow.
- 喵。
- No, no, Gare-bearings.
- 不，不，齿轮轴承。
You have to stay here at home.
你必须呆在家里。
[clank]
[sad foghorn blares]
[叮当声]
[悲伤的雾号声]
- Meow?
- 喵？
[chiming]
[鸣响]
- A little more to the left.
- 再往左边一点。
[mischievous music]
[恶作剧的音乐]
Almost there.
快到了。
P-p-p-perfect!
噗噗完美！
See you later, G-G-G-Gary.
再见，G-G-G-Gary。
- [sighs] Finally,
- [叹气]最后，
someone whose company
I actually enjoy--
某人的公司
我其实很享受——
me!
我！
- Ha ha ha.
- 哈哈哈。
- Time for work, Squidbot!
- 工作时间到了，Squidbot！
[siren wailing]
Time for work, Squidbot!
[警笛哀号]
工作时间到了，鱿鱼机器人！
Time for work, Squidbot!
- [grumbles]
Power down
- [抱怨]
断电
and leave me alone, SpongeBot!
别管我了，海绵机器人！
I've still got 15 minutes!
我还有15分钟！
- Oh, sorry, Squidbot!
- 哦，对不起，鱿鱼机器人！
Sorry, Squidbot!
对不起，鱿鱼机器人！
- [grunts] Go away!
- [咕哝]走开！
[beeping]
- I am going to have
[嘟嘟声]
- 我将会有
to live next to that?
住在旁边吗？
[beeps]
[嘟嘟声]
- [sighs]
[clanking]
- [叹气]
[叮当声]
- Knock, knock, knock.
- 敲，敲，敲。
Hey Pat-Tron,
I'm going to work!
嘿帕特隆，
我要去工作了！
- I'm going with you,
SpongeBot!
- 我和你一起去，
海绵机器人！
I gotta fuel up.
我得加油了
- Hooray!
- 万岁！
[voice fades]
[声音渐弱]
[buzzing]
[嗡嗡声]
- Pat-Tron is currently
in recharge mode.
- Pat-Tron 目前是
处于充电模式。
- [laughs]
OK, buddy.
- [笑]
好的，伙计。
I'll bring you some fuel
on my way back home.
我给你带点燃料
在我回家的路上。
[wheels squeaking]
[车轮吱吱作响]
- If you're going to be
late, give me the key.
- 如果你要成为
迟到了，给我钥匙。
- Ooh, sorry, Squidbot.
- 哦，对不起，Squidbot。
But... ♪ The key bone's
connected to the finger bone ♪
但是... ♪ 关键的骨头是
与指骨相连♪
[laughs]
[beeping]
[笑]
[嘟嘟声]
[clang]
[铛]
[sign buzzing]
[标志嗡嗡声]
- You're fired!
You're fired!
- 你被解雇了！
你被解雇了！
You're fired!
[clang]
[wheezes]
[叮当声]
[喘息声]
[blubbers]
[哭声]
Thank you, Bot-O.
谢谢你，Bot-O。
I got stuck in the firing mode.
我陷入了射击模式。
- Ahh, to be fired.
- 啊，被解雇了。
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
- Nobody's getting fired,
you robo-loafer.
- 没有人被解雇
你这个机器人游手好闲者。
Everybody get to work!
大家快去上班吧！
Whoa!
哇！
[beeps]
- Whoop!
[嘟嘟声]
- 哎呀！
The Krabby Batteries
are sizzlin'!
克拉比电池
太热了！
Now it's time for condiments.
现在是调味品的时间了。
[clanging]
[叮叮当当]
- Hmm.
- 唔。
[slurps]
[electricity zapping]
[啜饮]
[电击]
[yelping]
[尖叫]
- Food up, SpongeBot.
- 食物来了，海绵机器人。
Gimme two batteries on
a barge and make 'em cry.
给我两块电池
一艘驳船，让他们哭泣。
[whooshing]
[crash]
[呼啸]
[崩溃]
[electricity zapping]
[电击]
- Huh?
- Ahh!
- 啊？
- 啊！
[blubbering]
[哭泣]
- Robo-Gary?
- 机器人加里？
Squidbot?
鱿鱼机器人？
No!
不！
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
- [gurgling]
- [咯咯声]
- Gary-Squid?
- 加里鱿鱼？
Squid-Gary?
鱿鱼加里？
Does not compute.
不会计算。
[Gary yelps]
- Get your filthy
[加里尖叫]
- 收拾你的脏东西
robo-snail off my head!
机器人蜗牛从我头上掉下来了！
[straining]
[紧张]
- Gary!
[panting]
- 加里！
[气喘吁吁]
[Squidbot screams]
[鱿鱼机器人尖叫]
[clanking]
[exclaiming]
[叮当声]
[惊呼]
- Ay-ya-ya-ya-whoa!
- 哎呀呀呀哇！
[beeps]
[嘟嘟声]
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
- Ahh! Ahh!
- 啊！啊！
[crashing]
[崩溃]
I've gotta cut off
this pooping parasite!
我必须切断
这个拉屎的寄生虫！
- All right, what the kelp
is going on in here?
- 好吧，海带是什么
这里发生什么事了？
[growls]
[咆哮]
- [exclaims]
- [惊呼]
- Come back here, you
nickel-plated nincompoops!
- 回来吧，你
镀镍 nincompoops！
[grunts]
[powers down]
[咕哝]
[断电]
[cranking]
[启动]
- Plankbot, you forgot
to wind yourself again.
- Plankbot，你忘了
再次给自己上风。
- Thanks, Karen,
my flesh and blood wife.
- 谢谢，凯伦，
我的骨肉妻子。
Don't worry, I'll get him.
别担心，我会去找他的。
[growls]
- Hi, Karen.
[咆哮]
- 嗨，凯伦。
Did Gary come through here?
加里有来过这里吗？
- He went thataway, Chuckles.
- 他就走了，咯咯。
- Th-th-th-thank you!
- 谢谢你！
- Mama told me not
to marry a robot.
- 妈妈告诉我不是
嫁给一个机器人。
- Ahh!
Gangway!
- 啊！
舷梯！
Runaway robot!
逃跑的机器人！
[crashing]
[崩溃]
Ahh!
- Excuse me, pardon me,
啊！
- 对不起，原谅我，
Excuse me, pardon me.
- Ow!
对不起，原谅我。
- 噢！
Excuse me, pardon me.
对不起，原谅我。
[all grumbling]
[大家都在抱怨]
[shouting]
[喊叫]
- Ahh!
- 啊！
- Who disturbs the
sacred dome of Sandroid?
- 谁打扰了
Sandroid 的神圣圆顶？
I'll hogtie your actuators!
我会绑住你的执行器！
- Sandroid, wait!
- Sandroid，等等！
Gary is too young to have
his actuators hogtied!
加里还太年轻，不能拥有
他的执行器被绑住了！
- I'll hack your hard drives,
you cybernetic simpletons!
- 我会破解你的硬盘
你们这些控制论傻瓜！
[all clamoring]
Ow!
[全都吵闹]
噢！
- All right, there you go.
- 好吧，就这样吧。
- [growling]
- [咆哮]
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
- [slurping]
- [发出声音]
[dings]
[叮当声]
[whirring]
[呼呼]
- Robo-dog!
- 机器狗！
Get your robo-dog!
拿起你的机器狗！
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
[electricity zapping]
[电击]
[brakes screech]
[刹车声]
- Lube Lagoon?
- 润滑油泻湖？
What happened to Goo Lagoon?
古泻湖怎么了？
Where in space and time am I?
我在空间和时间的什么地方？
Looks like I took a wrong
turn at the last apocalypse.
看来我接错了
转向最后的启示录。
- Danger! Danger!
- Ah!
- 危险！危险！
- 啊！
Rogue Robot!
- Gary, wait!
流氓机器人！
- 加里，等等！
Come back!
[all shouting]
回来！
[大家大喊]
- Who dares defy Sandroid?
- 谁敢反抗Sandroid？
- I'm gonna destroy all of you!
- 我要毁掉你们所有人！
- [exclaims]
- [惊呼]
These junk heaps
want my flab for fuel!
这些垃圾堆
想要我的赘肉当燃料！
[tires screech]
[轮胎尖叫声]
- Ahh!
- 啊！
[mob shouting]
- No, Gary!
[暴民喊叫]
- 不，加里！
Not the lagoon!
不是泻湖！
What do I do now?
我现在该怎么办？
Got to think.
必须想一想。
[beeping]
[嘟嘟声]
That's it!
A brick wall!
就是这样！
砖墙！
[beeps]
[嘟嘟声]
[rocket whistling]
Ah! Ah! Ah! Ah!
[火箭呼啸]
啊！啊!啊!啊!
[crashing]
[崩溃]
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
[blows whistle]
Gary!
[吹口哨]
加里！
Stop!
停止！
- [meowing frantically]
- [疯狂地喵喵叫]
[tires screeching]
[轮胎的尖叫声]
- Gary, stop!
[horn blares]
- 加里，停下来！
[喇叭声]
Gary, stop!
[buzzer blares]
加里，停下来！
[蜂鸣器鸣响]
Gary, stop!
[bell dings]
加里，停下来！
[铃声]
He's not gonna stop.
他不会停下来。
- Ahh!
- 啊！
[mob shouting]
[暴民喊叫]
- Ahh!
- 啊！
[gasps]
Whoo-hoo!
[喘气]
呼呼！
[meowing]
[喵喵叫]
- Play nice with
the flutterbot!
- 玩得开心
扑扑机器人！
[all moaning]
[全都呻吟]
[ominous music]
[不祥的音乐]
[all gasping]
[全都喘气]
- Ahh!
- 啊！
[electricity crackling]
[电力噼啪声]
♪ ♪
- Meow?
- 喵？
- [exclaiming]
- [惊呼]
- [growling]
- [咆哮]
[roars]
[怒吼]
- Amazing!
- 惊人的！
[whirring]
[呼呼]
[shutter clicks]
[快门声]
- Flash photography
is forbidden
- 闪光摄影
被禁止
in the presence of Sandroid!
在Sandroid面前！
You will all be assimilated!
你们都会被同化！
So we can all be as close
as peas in a pod!
所以我们都可以如此亲密
就像豆荚里的豌豆一样！
Yee-haw!
呀呀！
- Oh man--
- 天啊--
[exclaims]
[惊呼]
- Well, this is another
fine metallic monstrosity
- 嗯，这是另一个
精致的金属怪物
you've got me into.
你让我陷入了困境。
- Look at it this way,
Squidbot.
- 这么看，
鱿鱼机器人。
Now we'll have
a chance to catch up
现在我们将有
有机会赶上
with all our neighbors.
与我们所有的邻居。
Hi, Rube.
- Well, hello!
嗨，鲁布。
- 嗯，你好！
- Typical.
[buzzes]
- 典型的。
[嗡嗡声]
Typical.
[buzzes]
典型的。
[嗡嗡声]
Typical.
[buzzes, babbles]
典型的。
[嗡嗡声，胡言乱语]
- Ahh--
[clang]
- 啊啊--
[叮当声]
[beeping]
[嘟嘟声]
[upbeat fiddle music]
[欢快的小提琴音乐]
- Rise of the robots!
- 机器人的崛起！
Yee-haw!
呀呀！
- I second that!
[roars]
- 我同意！
[怒吼]
[spooky music]
[诡异的音乐]
- Robots can never
replace us, you say?
- 机器人永远不能
你说取代我们？
Well, anything can
happen in a cartoon,
嗯，什么都可以
发生在动画片里，
especially if that cartoon
is from "The Tidal Zone."
尤其是如果那个卡通片
来自“潮汐区”。
[buzzes]
"The Tidal Zone."
[嗡嗡声]
“潮汐区。”
[buzzes]
"The Tidal Zone."
[嗡嗡声]
“潮汐区。”
"The Tidal Zone."
[buzzes]
[嗡嗡声]
“潮汐区。”